<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Chin.Mini Lab - Presentation</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/feeds/presentation.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://wcchin.github.io/</id><updated>2017-05-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Applying space-time information to explore disease processes: The dynamic patterns of Dengue Fever in Kaohsiung City, 1998-2015.</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/applying-space-time-information-to-explore-disease-processes-the-dynamic-patterns-of-dengue-fever-in-kaohsiung-city-1998-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-25T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Benny Chin</name></author><id>tag:wcchin.github.io,2017-05-25:/applying-space-time-information-to-explore-disease-processes-the-dynamic-patterns-of-dengue-fever-in-kaohsiung-city-1998-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Applying space-time information to explore disease processes: The dynamic patterns of Dengue Fever in Kaohsiung City, 1998-2015.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excellent Student Poster Award&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference:  The Annual Meeting of the Taiwan Chapter of Society for Risk Analysis (SRA‐Taiwan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date: May 25-26, 1300-1400 (Poster Session)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Taichung City Hall, Taichung City …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Applying space-time information to explore disease processes: The dynamic patterns of Dengue Fever in Kaohsiung City, 1998-2015.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excellent Student Poster Award&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference:  The Annual Meeting of the Taiwan Chapter of Society for Risk Analysis (SRA‐Taiwan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date: May 25-26, 1300-1400 (Poster Session)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Taichung City Hall, Taichung City, Taiwan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Room: Poster session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poster ID: A033&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen, Clive E. Sabel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dengue Fever (DF) data is recorded as a space-time point data, i.e. each record contains a spatial location, and a temporal location. Previous studies often use clustering analysis method to analyze this type of disease case data, to search for spatial or space-time cluster areas (hot-spots), and connect the clusters manually. The process between disease clusters has been neglected in previous studies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In disease diffusion processes, transmissions may experience a temporal lag for an incubation period, that is the time between infection and disease emergence. Thus a temporal lag between the transmission pairs should be considered in the understanding of disease diffusion. This can help to systematically model the disease diffusion process, and construct the relationships between cases and detect the process chains between clusters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the aim of this case study is to detect sub-clusters from the annual DF cases and identify processes between the sub-clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Link&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://srataiwan.fundot.tw/activity_show.aspx?id=20"&gt;about the conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://srataiwan.fundot.tw/activity_show.aspx?id=28"&gt;conference schedule&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Poster&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="pdfs/poster_tsra_2017.pdf"&gt;Poster link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Supplementary info&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://goo.gl/vZUGw2"&gt;animation of the diffusion process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Dengue Fever"></category><category term="disease diffusion"></category><category term="open data"></category><category term="TaPiTaS"></category><category term="Kaohsiung City"></category></entry><entry><title>Profiling topological characteristics of street network to identify urban traffic congestion</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/profiling-topological-characteristics-of-street-network-to-identify-urban-traffic-congestion.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Benny Chin</name></author><id>tag:wcchin.github.io,2016-12-01:/profiling-topological-characteristics-of-street-network-to-identify-urban-traffic-congestion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Profiling topological characteristics of street network to identify urban traffic congestion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: GSDI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date: Dec 01, 1330-1500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Nangang, Taipei, Taiwan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Room: 504b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theme: Smart Transportation/智慧運輸 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic: SDI for the Smart Homeland/智慧國土與空間資訊基礎建設&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a growing number of developing …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Profiling topological characteristics of street network to identify urban traffic congestion&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: GSDI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date: Dec 01, 1330-1500&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Nangang, Taipei, Taiwan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Room: 504b&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theme: Smart Transportation/智慧運輸 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic: SDI for the Smart Homeland/智慧國土與空間資訊基礎建設&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a growing number of developing cities, the capacities of roads cannot meet the rapidly growing demands of cars, causing congestion. Understanding the spatial-temporal process of traffic flow and detecting traffic congestion are important issues associated with developing urban policies to resolve congestion. The topological structure of a street network influences the turning probabilities between streets and the moving speeds of automobiles on those streets. Moreover, the connectivity of road segments reflects the degree of the road system facilitating people to their destination. Therefore, the objective of this study is to propose an innovative analytical procedure for investigating the traffic demands in terms of the traffic flow concentration and complexity of the road network based on turning probability. First, we proposed a flow-based ranking algorithm (Flow-based PageRank, FBPR) to determine the traffic flow concentration. Second, we analyzed the real volumes of vehicle movements to calibrate the turning probability. Finally, we measured the topological complexity in terms of outgoing entropy. Congested segments are defined as the street segments that are prone to traffic congestion. By overlapping the traffic demand in terms of FBPR scores and the topological complexity of street segments, congested segments can be identified. The results show that by relying on the topological characteristics of streets, most congested segments identified in the study successfully included the streets identified as the ten most congested streets or segments with slow moving speeds based on vehicle detector (VD) monitoring. The congested segments might also be sources of traffic congestion. Traffic demands can be determined by FBPR scores, which capture human movements, and street complexity can be measured by the outgoing entropy, which represents the topological complexity in terms of turning probability. We also examined the association of urban land use types with traffic demand and street complexity. Identifying the topological characteristics of traffic congestion provides comprehensive insights for city planners, and these characteristics can be used to further understand congestion spreading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Link&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://gsdi15.org.tw/
http://gsdi15.org.tw/Content/pdf/SessionsOfPresentation_論文發表議程.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Presentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://bit.ly/gsdi2016chin&lt;br&gt;
https://wcchin.github.io/ipyslides/gsdi2016/GSDI_2016_Wenlab.slides.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="800" height="600" src="https://wcchin.github.io/ipyslides/gsdi2016/GSDI_2016_Wenlab.slides.html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="open data"></category><category term="urban traffic"></category><category term="web-framework"></category><category term="processing"></category></entry><entry><title>從路段的連接性與流率分析城市內街道的流量以探討城市交通擁塞問題</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/cong-lu-duan-de-lian-jie-xing-yu-liu-lu-fen-xi-cheng-shi-nei-jie-dao-de-liu-liang-yi-tan-tao-cheng-shi-jiao-tong-yong-sai-wen-ti.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-16T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-10-16T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Benny Chin</name></author><id>tag:wcchin.github.io,2016-10-16:/cong-lu-duan-de-lian-jie-xing-yu-liu-lu-fen-xi-cheng-shi-nei-jie-dao-de-liu-liang-yi-tan-tao-cheng-shi-jiao-tong-yong-sai-wen-ti.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Understanding urban traffic congestion by analyzing the link structure and the vehicle flows of urban street network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: 發展研究年會&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: 國立台灣大學，台北市,台灣&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: Mandarin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;摘要:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;城市的交通擁塞，是全球各大城市每天都會面臨的一個問題。車輛的每一趟移動被稱爲旅次，而旅次的發生在於人需要從一個地方前往到另一個地方。在一趟的旅次中，車子的路徑會經過不少的路段。而這些路段之間，因爲相互交錯而提供移動的連接性。路網的設計，除了寬度、最高與最低速限，車道數等物理結構方面的特性之外，還有一個關鍵是其拓撲架構—連接性。連接性高的路段，表示透過這個路段可以很快的到達更多的目的地，故也會有較多的車輛會選擇經過這個路段 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Understanding urban traffic congestion by analyzing the link structure and the vehicle flows of urban street network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: 發展研究年會&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: 國立台灣大學，台北市,台灣&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: Mandarin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;摘要:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;城市的交通擁塞，是全球各大城市每天都會面臨的一個問題。車輛的每一趟移動被稱爲旅次，而旅次的發生在於人需要從一個地方前往到另一個地方。在一趟的旅次中，車子的路徑會經過不少的路段。而這些路段之間，因爲相互交錯而提供移動的連接性。路網的設計，除了寬度、最高與最低速限，車道數等物理結構方面的特性之外，還有一個關鍵是其拓撲架構—連接性。連接性高的路段，表示透過這個路段可以很快的到達更多的目的地，故也會有較多的車輛會選擇經過這個路段。路網的拓撲結構反映的是各個路段的供給面上，其能夠提供車輛移動的效率。而交通擁塞問題的另一關鍵，是旅次需求的分佈，亦即車輛在各個路段上移動的流率。流率越高，則路段的使用率高，當這些路段附近發生擁塞狀況時，這些地方將也很快的被影響。故，本研究將試着分析路段的連接性與流率等特性，討論擁塞的空間分佈。本研究透過應用部分路段的流量資訊，調校並應用 PageRank (PR) 演算法，分析路段與路口所組成的路網結構。並且，透過調校所取得的吸引程度資訊，討論路段的車輛轉向複雜度，以及計算最終的PR分數，推估每一條路段的潛在交通需求比例分佈。最後，透過套疊高轉向複雜度與高交通需求比例的路段，找出容易形成擁塞的路段。這些同時具備高轉向率與高交通需求比例的路段，主要分佈在官方公佈的十大擁塞路段以及透過街道車輛偵測器所找出的平均移動速度較低的路段的附近，說明轉向複雜度與交通需求比例是造成擁塞的潛在因子。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Presentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://bit.ly/acds2016chin&lt;br&gt;
https://wcchin.github.io/ipyslides/acds2016/network-congestion-06-acds.slides.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="800" height="600" src="https://wcchin.github.io/ipyslides/acds2016/network-congestion-06-acds.slides.html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="network"></category><category term="pagerank"></category><category term="flow"></category></entry><entry><title>Link structure analysis of urban road networks for identifying traffic impact areas</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/link-structure-analysis-of-urban-road-networks-for-identifying-traffic-impact-areas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-06-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Benny Chin</name></author><id>tag:wcchin.github.io,2016-06-02:/link-structure-analysis-of-urban-road-networks-for-identifying-traffic-impact-areas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Link structure analysis of urban road networks for identifying traffic impact areas&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: NetSci&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Seoul, South Korea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen, Pei-Chun Lai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the growing number of large cities, traffic congestion became a global issue. Identifying where it could occur is the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Link structure analysis of urban road networks for identifying traffic impact areas&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: NetSci&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Seoul, South Korea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen, Pei-Chun Lai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the growing number of large cities, traffic congestion became a global issue. Identifying where it could occur is the first question to resolve congestion. However, predicting the geographic extent of the congestion has seldom been discussed. Traffic impact areas (TIA) refer to areas that will be affected by traffic events. This study will explore more spatial factors that influence the TIA, including traffic flow and link topology of road network. We propose a novel flow-based analytical framework of ranking scheme to quantify interplay between urban road segments and identify the TIA. PageRank (PR) is the ranking algorithm used by Google Search Engine that calculates the scores of importance to rank and identify the significant webpages. PR assumes that people move randomly between webpages. Thus, the weights of all links are equal. However, human movement is not a random event. It is influenced by both network structure and an individual options. This study proposes a revised PR, Flow-based PageRank (FBPR), as the ranking scheme for road network. The weights of link structure in the proposed algorithm emphasize the attraction of road segments’ local properties, and determine the distribution of traffic volume between road segments. Actual traffic volume data is used with a genetic algorithm to fit the FBPR model (figure 1a) for calibrating the attractiveness. The TIA is affected by the extent of interplay, where stronger interplay triggers a larger impact. The interplay is defined as the strength of traffic flow between roads. We establish a community indices to map the interplay. Then, the TIA can be identified (figure 1b). In summary, the FBPR can be used to construct link structure among roads, and the communities identified in the road network represent TIA. It could provide more insights of traffic management for city planners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Link&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://netsci2016.net/download/program/19Diffusion_and_Transport.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Presentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://bit.ly/netsci2016benny&lt;br&gt;
https://wcchin.github.io/ipyslides/netsci2016/network-congestion-05.slides.html&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="800" height="600" src="https://wcchin.github.io/ipyslides/netsci2016/network-congestion-05.slides.html" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="spatial-temporal"></category><category term="web-framework"></category></entry><entry><title>A Web-based Framework for Monitoring Spatial-temporal Clustering of Epidemics in Taiwan</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/a-web-based-framework-for-monitoring-spatial-temporal-clustering-of-epidemics-in-taiwan.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-17T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-09-17T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Benny Chin</name></author><id>tag:wcchin.github.io,2015-09-17:/a-web-based-framework-for-monitoring-spatial-temporal-clustering-of-epidemics-in-taiwan.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Web-based Framework for Monitoring Spatial-temporal Clustering of Epidemics in Taiwan&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: FOSS4G&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Seoul, South Korea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen, Fei-Ying Kuo, Hwa-Lung Yu, Ming-Che Hu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the study is to propose a web-based early-warning framework for monitoring spatial-temporal clustering of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A Web-based Framework for Monitoring Spatial-temporal Clustering of Epidemics in Taiwan&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: FOSS4G&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2015&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Seoul, South Korea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen, Fei-Ying Kuo, Hwa-Lung Yu, Ming-Che Hu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of the study is to propose a web-based early-warning framework for monitoring spatial-temporal clustering of epidemics in Taiwan. The framework integrated disease surveillance data from difference sources, including Real-time Outbreak and Disease Surveillance (RODS) database, and LABoratory Surveillance (LABS) databases. RODS database is reported directly from the hospital emergency department (ED), whereas LABS is reported with detail information of the specific pathogen after the laboratory diagnosis procedures from contract hospitals. RODS could provide real-time information of patients’ symptoms but it provides nothing about confirmed disease or pathogens of a patient. LABS, on the other hand, could identify the specific infectious pathogen, which is the cause of disease, but the report time could have time lags due to laboratory diagnosis procedures. By combining open source tools and space-time clustering detections methods, we developed an early-warning framework for depicting space-time dynamics of clusters and identifying possible epidemic outbreaks. The framework is a web-based platform with several modules:1. Data Explore: it includes data management, data processing and space-time data visualization; 2. Space-Time Analyst: it analyzes space-time relationships of cases and depicts space-time dynamics of clusters by developing ST-DBSCAN algorithm, and 3. Early-Warning Alert: it provides real-time alerts when detecting possible disease outbreaks. The platform is established in Python environment. We used several open source components, including web2py as the web-based framework (system core component) and Bokeh for data visualization. The system core component is the control centers for dealing with requests/responses, scheduled analysis procedures and database updates. We also built a Postgresql/PostGIS database to store/manage the geographic information and disease data extracted from RODS and LABS databases. The visualization components used several javascript libraries, including leafletjs, mapbox, and bokehjs. The Space-Time Analyst and Early-Warning Alert modules were developed with open source Python libraries for identifying the space-time process of reported cases, including the dynamics of the core-border-noise changes, the space-time clusters, and the space-time association between RODS-LABS events. Our study built a web-based spatial decision support system with the two disease surveillance databases (RODS and LABS). With the integration of open source packages and libraries, we built the comprehensive prototype for early warning of detecting the disease clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Link&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.meci.co.kr/societyevent/FOSS4G2015/program/program_view.asp?a_type=PT&amp;amp;a_idx=81&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Presentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://bit.ly/foss4g2015chin&lt;br&gt;
http://wcchin.github.io/ipyslides/foss4g2015/FOSS4G_seoul2015.slides.html?theme=sky?transition=convex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="800" height="600" src="http://wcchin.github.io/ipyslides/foss4g2015/FOSS4G_seoul2015.slides.html?theme=sky?transition=convex" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="spatial-temporal"></category><category term="web-framework"></category></entry><entry><title>考量地理特性的 PageRank 演算法： 評估地理網絡節點之重要性</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/kao-liang-di-li-te-xing-de-pagerank-yan-suan-fa-ping-gu-di-li-wang-luo-jie-dian-zhi-zhong-yao-xing.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-26T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-04-26T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Benny Chin</name></author><id>tag:wcchin.github.io,2014-04-26:/kao-liang-di-li-te-xing-de-pagerank-yan-suan-fa-ping-gu-di-li-wang-luo-jie-dian-zhi-zhong-yao-xing.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Geographically modified PageRank algorithms: Measuring the importance of nodes in a geospatial network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: 中國地理學會年會&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: 國立台灣大學，台北市,台灣&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: Mandarin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aims to proposed two geographically modified diffusion-based algorithms, to figure out where people live their lives. Since human movements …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Geographically modified PageRank algorithms: Measuring the importance of nodes in a geospatial network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: 中國地理學會年會&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: 國立台灣大學，台北市,台灣&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: Mandarin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study aims to proposed two geographically modified diffusion-based algorithms, to figure out where people live their lives. Since human movements reflects the locations where the daily lives of people occurred, a transportation network, which represent how places connect with each other by transportation system, could be used to uncover the spatial distribution pattern of the people’s daily lives. PageRank (PR), a successful diffusion-based algorithm, is what Google uses to determine how important a webpage is on the World Wide Web. However, most measures of network analysis, including PR, were designed to understand network topological structures rather than geographical structures. In other words, these measures have not considered the geographical constraints as their main concern. This study incorporates geographic properties, including distance-decay and gravity model among nodes, and proposes two modified PR algorithms, the Inversed-Distance PageRank (IDPR), and Geographical PageRank (GPR). To test the performance of the IDPR and GPR, this study calculated the IDPR and GPR for the inter-city network of Taiwan. Then, we used the population data and inter-townships car flow data as observed data to understand the correlation between them, and compared the correlation results with the correlations calculated with the existing algorithms, including PR and Weighted PageRank (WPR), and three centrality measurements, including degree, closeness, and betweenness. The results showed that IDPR and GPR are better correlated with the observed data. Since IDPR and GPR take the distance decay effect into account, results using the algorithms can capture more geographical properties. In conclusion, while dealing with a geographical issue, which distance decay effect existed, IDPR and GPR are better algorithms to be used in the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Keywords&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PageRank, distance decay, gravity model, geospatial network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;摘要:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本研究旨在提出兩個以地理特性修改之擴散式演算法,以討論人的生活環境空間的分佈。因人的生活的所在空間可以透過人的移動所反映,反應地方之間如何相連的交通網絡可以用以揭示人類生活空間的空間分佈形態。PageRank (PR),是一個擴散式演算法,其是 Google 搜尋引擎背後從網際網路中找出重要網頁的主要演算法。然而,大多數網絡分析的評量方法,包括 PR,皆以分析網絡拓撲結構為主要目的,而地理結構則並非其主要分析目的。換言之,這些評量方法並沒有將地理的限制納入其分析的考量。因此,本研究將地理特性,包括地方與地方之間的互動強度的距離遞減效果及引力模型特性與PageRank 演算法做整合,並提出兩個地理特性修改之 PageRank 演算法,包括Inversed-Distance PageRank (IDPR), 及 Geographical PageRank (GPR)。為了解IDPR 及 GPR 捕捉重要節點之能力,本研究將人口及城際運輸流量資料作為觀察資料,與計算所得之 IDPR 及 GPR 的結果做相關分析,並與已存在的 PR 及Weighted PageRank (WPR) ,及傳統網絡分析之中心性指標 (centrality) 之相關分析結果做比較。結果顯示,IDPR 及 GPR 與觀察資料有較高的相關性。因 IDPR及 GPR 都有考量距離遞減效果,因此其能夠捕捉較多的地理特性以運用於演算法中,並產出具考量地理特性之重要性分佈的結果。因此,當我們在討論具有地理特性之議題並分析其地理空間網絡時,IDPR 與 GPR 是較好的演算法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;關鍵字&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PageRank, 距離遞減, 引力模型, 地理空間網絡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Presentation -&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="svgs/geogsoc_2014.svg" target="blank"&gt; 研討會簡報檔 &lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;點擊滑鼠左鍵下一頁，右鍵上一頁，中鍵(滾輪)大綱跳頁
&lt;object id="svg1" data="svgs/geogsoc_2014.svg" type="image/svg+xml" style="width: 650px; height: 480px"&gt;&lt;/object&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="network"></category><category term="pagerank"></category></entry><entry><title>Geographically modified PageRank Algorithm: Measuring the importance of nodes in a geospatial network</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/geographically-modified-pagerank-algorithm-measuring-the-importance-of-nodes-in-a-geospatial-network.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-04-09T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Benny Chin</name></author><id>tag:wcchin.github.io,2013-04-09:/geographically-modified-pagerank-algorithm-measuring-the-importance-of-nodes-in-a-geospatial-network.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Geographically modified PageRank Algorithm: Measuring the importance of nodes in a geospatial network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: AAG Annual Meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Los Angeles, California, USA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A geospatial network represents the spatial relationships with the network perspective.  Within the scope of social network analysis …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Geographically modified PageRank Algorithm: Measuring the importance of nodes in a geospatial network&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: AAG Annual Meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2013&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Los Angeles, California, USA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A geospatial network represents the spatial relationships with the network perspective.  Within the scope of social network analysis, the network topology characteristics, including network centrality, small world and scale-free properties, have been well studied, and these concepts can also provide important implications on measuring the important of places in the geospatial network. However, most measures of social network analysis were designed to understand network topological structures rather than geographical structures. Therefore, these measures have not considered the geographical relationships as their main concern, including geographical distance between nodes and distance-decay property. PageRank, a link analysis algorithm, is what Google uses to determine how important a page is on the web. This study incorporates geographic properties, including distance-decay and spatial interactions among nodes, with traditional PageRank algorithm and proposes two modified PageRank algorithms, Distance-Inverse PageRank (DiPR) and Geographical PageRank (GPR), and compared the performance with existing algorithms: PageRank and Weighted PageRank. We demonstrate the use of these four algorithms with Taiwan city network, and compare our calculation results with existing network centrality metrics (degree, betweenness, closeness and eigenvector). Then, we calculated the Spearman's rho between our calculation results and population and transportation flow data. Our findings show that DiPR and GPR are better correlated to population distribution and transportation flow than other metrics.  Since DiPR and GPR take the distance decay effect into account, results using the algorithms can capture more geographical properties. Our findings suggest that DiPR and GPR are better metrics to be used in geospatial network analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Keywords&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;distance decay, spatial interaction, PageRank, social network analysis, geospatial network &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Link&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://meridian.aag.org/callforpapers/program/AbstractDetail.cfm?AbstractID=51232&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Presentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://prezi.com/ccz0fhq00yun/?utm_campaign=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=copy&amp;amp;rc=ex0share&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe id="iframe_container" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen="" width="550" height="400" src="https://prezi.com/embed/65e65d6d006c32ed7ba8009c571e9141996adddc/?bgcolor=ffffff&amp;amp;lock_to_path=0&amp;amp;autoplay=0&amp;amp;autohide_ctrls=0&amp;amp;landing_data=bHVZZmNaNDBIWnNjdEVENDRhZDFNZGNIUE43MHdLNWpsdFJLb2ZHanI5Z1RMM0llb3RpNzFhOVBMZmRuVDhCdjJBPT0&amp;amp;landing_sign=7sGHmctsFT0dhKkpZAqY4cfy3cxQv1qrrYK-4YXYfJI"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><category term="network"></category><category term="pagerank"></category></entry><entry><title>整合PageRank與空間互動模型於網絡都市的拓樸動態分析</title><link href="https://wcchin.github.io/zheng-he-pagerankyu-kong-jian-hu-dong-mo-xing-yu-wang-luo-du-shi-de-tuo-pu-dong-tai-fen-xi.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-21T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2012-04-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Benny Chin</name></author><id>tag:wcchin.github.io,2012-04-21:/zheng-he-pagerankyu-kong-jian-hu-dong-mo-xing-yu-wang-luo-du-shi-de-tuo-pu-dong-tai-fen-xi.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Integration of PageRank and Spatial Interaction Modeling to Analyze Topological Dynamics of Networked Cities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: 中國地理學會年會&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: 中國文化大學，台北市,台灣&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: Mandarin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper used PageRank concept to analyse cities network, to understand the shift of network cities’ position after the construction …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Integration of PageRank and Spatial Interaction Modeling to Analyze Topological Dynamics of Networked Cities&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference: 中國地理學會年會&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year: 2012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: 中國文化大學，台北市,台灣&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language: Mandarin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors: Wei-Chien Benny-Chin, Tzai-Hung Wen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abstract&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper used PageRank concept to analyse cities network, to understand the shift of network cities’ position after the construction of Taiwan High-Speed-Rail (THSR). The integration of network analysis and spatial analysis shows advantages in capturing transitive effect and spatial dependence effect, which has made the cities spatial interaction modeling analysis could better represent the interactive relationship between cities. THSR is an important development in recent year, which across several counties in Taiwan, and has caused significant changes and affects on the interactions between regionals. Thus, this paper focuses on changes in internal structure of cities network’s topological dynamics after the construction of THSR. This paper was divided into 3 parts: in the first part, we constructed 2 sets of cities network as relationships of cities before and after the THSR, and analysed these networks with PageRank, Weighted PageRank, Distance-Inverse PageRank, Gravity PageRank; in the second part, we try to compare the distribution of the change of rank after the construction of THSR between these models; finally, we used Dual Kernel Density Estimation to analyse spatial-temporal changes of rank after the construction of THSR. In conclusion, we found that the results of 4 models varied between each other, which suggested these models could capture different characteristics and effects of cities network.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Keywords&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cities network analysis, network topological dynamic, Taiwan High Speed Rail, PageRank, Weighted PageRank&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;摘要:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文以PageRank的網絡分析方法，分析各都市的網絡結構，以了解在高鐵的建設前後，都市在網絡中的地位之空間分佈及變化趨勢。網絡分析與地理空間分析的整合可以同時捕捉網絡的遞移性與空間的地緣效果，因此空間互動模型分析可以更有效的反映都市間的互動關係。高鐵的建設是台灣近期跨數個縣市的重大發展之一，其對台灣各區域的互動關係造成大幅度的變化及影響。因此，本文著重討論高鐵建設前後，都市網絡內在結構的拓撲動態，及其對城市排名變化趨勢的影響。本研究分為三個部分，第一部分為建立兩組網絡，分別為高鐵建設前的都市網絡及高鐵建設後的都市網絡，並以 PageRank、Weighted PageRank、及加入距離遞減概念的Distance Inverse PageRank、與整合引力模型概念的Gravity PageRank，對兩組都市網絡拓撲結構進行分析；第二部分對城市節點的分數進行排序以討論高鐵興建前後的城市排名變化趨勢；第三部分以Dual Kernel Density Estimation 對兩組網絡的地位分佈進行時空變遷分析。上述分析結果顯示，高鐵的建設在四種指標所反映的狀況並不相同，各指標所呈現及捕捉的效果也有所不同。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;關鍵字&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;都市網絡分析,網絡拓撲動態,台灣高鐵,PageRank,Weighted PageRank&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Presentation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/BennyChin4/page-rank-70015993&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/LfHjwgB2Uy72cN" width="595" height="485" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style="margin-bottom:5px"&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="//www.slideshare.net/BennyChin4/page-rank-70015993" title="整合Page rank 與空間互動模型於網絡都市的拓撲分析" target="_blank"&gt;整合Page rank 與空間互動模型於網絡都市的拓撲分析&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="//www.slideshare.net/BennyChin4"&gt;Benny Chin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="network"></category><category term="pagerank"></category></entry></feed>